我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我来理一下
Let me get this straight.
你是我们认识的威尔斯博士的二重身
You're the doppelganger of our Dr. Wells.
是的  但是那个威尔斯博士的身体
Yeah, but that Dr. Wells' body had been taken over
被逆闪电夺取了  也就是艾尔伯德·斯旺
by the Reverse Flash, who was really Eobard Thawne.
艾迪
Eddie!
别死去  好吧  不要
Stay with me, okay? Stay.
艾迪是他的先人
Eddie's his ancestor.
如果艾迪死了  他就不会出生
If Eddie dies, then Thawne will never be born.
他的存在将被抹除
He'll be erased from existence!
哈特利·拉瑟威  如果不是他
Hartley Rathaway. I couldn't have built
我造不出粒子加速器
the particle accelerator without him.
-西斯科  你看见什么了  -我看见杰伊了
- Cisco, what did you see? - I saw Jay.
他就是极速
He's Zoom.
我又犯了同样的错误
I let it happen again.
相信了不该相信的人
I trusted someone I shouldn't have.
杰伊·加里克就是极速
Jay Garrick. Zoom.
就像我之前相信了哈里森·威尔斯
Just like I trusted Harrison Wells,
或者说是艾尔伯德·斯旺
or Eobard Thawne.
你明白我的意思吗
You see what I mean?
同样的错误我犯了两次
I made the same mistake twice.
我以为他们是想教我如何
I thought they wanted to teach me how
利用我的能力  如何跑得更快
to use my powers, train me to get faster,
但其实他们不是来帮我的
but they didn't come here to help me.
他们是来利用我的
They came to use me
并把我所爱的一切都夺走
and take everything I love away from me.
以后不会这样了
But no more.
我会破解出方法
I'm gonna crack the code.
想出提高我速度的办法
Figure out how to improve my speed.
我会更加努力地训练  变得更强大
I'm gonna train harder, get stronger,
成为跑得最快的人
and run faster than anyone's ever run before.
然后我就会阻止极速
And then I'm gonna stop Zoom.
能不能把杰伊的头盔扔掉
Can we please get rid of Jay's helmet?
不能  抱歉  它能让我有动力
No, sorry. It keeps me motivated.
可它能让我大白天做恶梦
Well, it's giving me daymares.
这是我所能找到的所有资料
This is everything I could find
甚至有些跟提高速度都关系很小
even remotely related to increasing speed.
这些怎么会帮到你
How are these supposed to help
解出这个速度公式呢
apply the speed equation to you?
答案肯定就在其中
The answer's got to be here somewhere.
我好像发现了点东西
I think I found something interesting.
好东西还是坏东西
Good interesting or bad interesting?
这可是有两种可能的
'Cause that word could go either way.
在做了一些数据比较之后
After running some comparative data,
我发现你  逆闪电还有极速
it appears that you, Reverse Flash, and Zoom
腿的摆动速度基本都一样
are moving your legs at essentially the same speed.
那他们为什么都比他快呢
Then why are they so much faster than him?
我现在能发现的就是  每跨一步时
Best I can tell, with each stride
他们的脚踩地的时间比较短
their feet spend less time on the ground,
这样他们就把自己更快地推向前方
thus propelling them forward much faster.
将近快百分之三十  真好
By almost 30%. Great.
好吧  我们得想办法解决这个问题
All right, well, I got to make up that difference somehow.
巴里
Barry?
那个混蛋所做的事
Look, after what that monster did,
让我和你一样很想阻止杰伊
I want to stop Jay just as badly as you do...
是的
Right.
可是  有没有可能你之所以
But what if the reason you haven't been able to run
跑得不如他快  是因为你根本不可能呢
as fast as him yet is because you just can't?
巴里  你明白杰伊的事并不怪你  对吧
Barry, you know what happened to Jay is not your fault, right?
我应该早就看穿的
Well, I should've known better.
你  有了去年威尔斯的事
You? With Wells last year,
我应该吸取教训
I should've learned my lesson
好好调查一下杰伊  可是我没有
and dug deeper into Jay, but... I didn't.
别这样  乔
Come on, Joe.
我的意思是  没人预料到会这样
Point being is nobody saw this coming.
没人
Nobody.
所以  我
So I...
算是进行了场约会
kind of went on a date.
跟谁
With who?
《中城时报》的新编辑
The new editor at CCPN.
斯科特·埃文斯
Scott Evans.
你的老板吗
Your boss?
好吧  不是你想的那样
Okay, it wasn't like that.
他是个好男人
He's a really nice guy.
很体贴  很聪明  而且
He's sweet and smart and...
什么
What?
让我  让我想起了艾迪
It just-- it all makes me think about Eddie.
我每天都在想他  巴里
I think about him every day, Barry.
我感觉这样不对
It just feels wrong.
我肯定艾迪想让你找到新恋人
I know for a fact that Eddie would want you to find love again.
是的  我知道  但是
Yeah, I know, but--
听我说  爱瑞丝
Look, Iris.
只有你自己才知道什么时候
You're the only person who's gonna know
能够放下过去向前看  但在那之前
when you're ready to move on, but until then
不要把自己封闭起来
don't keep yourself completely closed off, you know?
否则你会错过一些美好的事情
You're gonna miss out on something great.
好的
Yeah.
抱歉  我迟到了
Hey, sorry I'm late.
没有  没有  时间刚刚好
No, no, you're just in time.
老爸  戴手套
Dad! Mittens!
我的指导老师很喜欢我设计的引擎
So... my advisor loved my engine designs
甚至让我帮她
and even asked me to help her out with one
-完成她的一项引擎项目  -学霸啊
- of her engineering projects. - Okay, big man on campus.
没有那么厉害
It's not that big a deal.
是个很好的机会  你应该抓住
It's a great opportunity, and you should take it
因为机会不是经常都有的
because life doesn't give those out all the time.
我说的对吧  巴里
Isn't that right, Barry?
没错
Yeah.
没错  那项目是要做什么来的
Yeah. What is the project about?
是想要用小型推进系统
It's trying to push the speed limits
突破速度的极限
with smaller propulsion systems.
-是挺酷的  -你要从何开始
- Yeah, that's cool. - Where do you even start?
我特想读读经典工程学专家们的笔记
Well, I really like to read the journals of the classic engineers,
他们如何设计引擎  怎么增加马力的
so their engine designs, how they increase horsepower,
名师出高徒吧  大概
and learn from the best, I guess.
你读了他们的笔记
You read their journals?
我是说  我又不能直接
I mean, it's not like I can
去和恩佐·法拉利
just go and talk to Enzo Ferrari
或是斐迪南·保时捷对话  因为他们死了
or Ferdinand Porsche 'cause they dead, but...
但是不代表他们不能继续教我东西了
You know, doesn't mean they can't still teach me.
我得走了
I got to go.
你都没碰你的食物
You haven't even touched your food.
是没  抱歉  我只是...
Yeah, no, I'm sorry. I just, um--
我只是刚想到破我手上案子的关键
I just realized the key to a case I've been working on,
所以我得  谢谢你  沃利
so I'm gonna just-thank you, Wally.
抱歉各位
Um, sorry, guys.
我会  我等下就回来
I'll be--I'll be back later.
这家伙每见一次都会变得更奇怪
That dude gets weirder every time I see him.
是啊
Yeah.
你是说"老的"哈里森·威尔斯
You mean the "Old" Harrison Wells?
也就是艾尔伯德·斯旺
As in Eobard Thawne?
你想让他教你如何跑得更快吗
You want him to teach you how to run faster?
-可真大胆  -你要怎么办到呢
- Oh, that's rich. - How are you gonna do that?
跑回到去年的某个时间点
By running back to a time last year.
那另一个你怎么办
And what about the other you,
在那个时间线上的你
the one from that other timeline?
我会用什么东西敲晕他
I'll knock him out with something.
我是说  他肯定不会想到我会过去
I mean, he's not like he'll see me coming,
然后我就让威尔斯教我
and then I'll have Wells teach me.
巴里  这太疯狂了
Barry, that's crazy.
我所读到的一切无法给我解决办法
Nothing I've read is pointing me towards a solution,
如果能有谁可以想出
and if there's anybody that's figured out
不使用V9就可以变快的诀窍  只有他
the key to getting faster without V-9, it's him.
你们怎么想
What do you guys think?
你的计划愚蠢至极
Your plan is asinine.
你找到杰西了吗
Did you find Jesse?
我看起来像是找到杰西了吗
Does it look like I found Jesse?
你穿越时间多少次了
How many times have you traveled through time?
几次
A few.
你知道你能搞砸多少事情吗
Do you have any idea how many things you could screw up?
我只需要和威尔斯博士进行一次对话
All I need is one conversation with Dr. Wells.
-他不是威尔斯  -斯旺
- He's not Wells. - Thawne.
我才是威尔斯  那个男人研究了你
I'm Wells! This man has been studying you
十五年  整整十五年
for 15 years-for 15 years--
你觉得他不会发现你是谁吗
and you don't think he's gonna know who you are?
巴里对模仿他自己挺在行的
Barry's pretty good at impersonating himself.
你应该看看他在地球二时候的表现
You should've seen him over there on Earth-2.
我都心想  "谁来给他个奥斯卡奖吧"
I was like, "Somebody get this man an Oscar."
他会知道的  艾伦  他会知道的
He will know, Allen. He will know.
好吧  那我要怎么办
All right, then what am I supposed to do?
我是说  我要怎么才能阻止极速
I mean, how am I supposed to stop Zoom?
你知道这个公式的解吗
Do you know the answer to this equation?
如果斯旺发现了那是你
If Thawne figures out that it's you,
时间线就会更改
the timeline will be altered.
可能会有人死
People can die.
其他人可能会活过来  谁也不知道
Others could live, and no one will know
谁或是什么会被影响  但我向你保证
who or what will be affected, but I promise you,
当你回来的时候  肯定会有变化
when you come back, things will be different.
而只有你知道发生了哪些变化
And only you will know what those differences are.
如果只有这样我才能阻止极速的话
Well, if that's what I have to do to stop Zoom,
那也无妨  因为我不这么做
then so be it, because if I don't,
一旦极速在我学会如何阻止他之前偷走我速度
and Zoom gets my speed before I learn how to stop him,
所有我关心的人  在这座城市的所有人
everybody I care about, everybody in this whole city--
他们的世界一样也会发生变化
their world will never be the same anyway.
你真的认为你可以做到吗
Do you really think you can do this?
是的
Yeah, I do.
当我去年回到过去看到母亲死亡后
When I went back last year and I saw my mom die,
时间线没有因此而改变
it didn't affect the timeline.
是  但你之前并没有像今天这样
Yeah, but you haven't really time traveled
有意的进行时间旅行
on purpose like this before.
我必须得这么做
I have to do this, you guys.
好吧  那我们就放手一搏
Okay, let's go for it.
好的  你要回到的时间点
Okay, you're gonna go back to the time
是威尔斯正在被一个超级大混蛋
when Wells was distracted by the return
哈特利·拉瑟威搅得心神不静的时候
of the major jackass, Hartley Rathaway.
这时候我们刚发现
This is the first time we found out
威尔斯知道粒子加速器会爆炸
Wells knew the accelerator might explode,
我们都对他很生气
and we were all angry with him,
所以你任何看起来奇怪的举动
so anything that might seem odd about your behavior
威尔斯可能都会归结于这事上
Wells should attribute to that.
还有要记得
Also remember:
不要低估哈特利  他差点就杀死了你
do not underestimate Hartley. He almost killed you.
这个镇静镖应该能让"老的"你昏睡六小时
This is a tranq dart that should knock "Old" you out for about six hours,
时间刚好足够支撑到你回来
which lines up perfectly for when you're going back,
因为那天没什么意外
because not much was happening
直到晚上哈特利攻击克利夫兰水坝
until Hartley attacked the Cleveland Dam that night,
威尔斯的家被蓄意破坏
拉瑟威工业区遭到攻击
所以应该可以给你足够时间学习然后回来
so that should give you time to learn what you need and return.
哈特利逃出牢房去往水坝
克利夫兰水坝大骚乱
还有一件事  你不能告诉我们
One more thing. You cannot tell us
关于威尔斯的真相  不管发生什么
the truth about Wells, no matter what.
你必须保持时间线的稳定
You must keep the timeline intact.
如果发生了变化
It's gonna be hard to course correct
就很难纠正回来了  所以找到你想要的
if anything gets altered, so get what you need
然后回来  最好是到这个时刻
and come back, preferably to this moment,
这个你离开的准确时刻  不然你可能会陷入
this exact time you're leaving, or else you might set off some
类似《十二猴子》里那样的时间轮回无法逃离
kind of "12 Monkeys" time loop you'll never get out of.
-别有压力  -好吧
- No pressure. - Yeah. Cool.
所以  我们等  两秒后见
So, we'll see you in, like, two seconds.
时间旅行真诡异
Time travel's so weird.
-祝你成功  巴里  -我会没事的
- Godspeed, Barry. - I'll be fine.
能出什么差错
What could go wrong?
艾迪
Eddie!
不好  我来早了
Oh, no. I'm too early.
你知道我名字  我也知道些名字
You know my name? I know some names too.
这开局可不妙
This is not a good start.
凯特琳·斯诺
Caitlin Snow.
西斯科·拉蒙  哈里森·威尔斯
Cisco Ramon. Harrison Wells.
拉瑟威
他的通讯器受到了干扰
Something's interfering with his comms.
巴里
Barry!
怎么回事  该死
Come on! Damn it.
-怎么回事  -我不知道
- What's happening? - I don't know.
拉瑟威工业
哈特利肯定让他的通讯器短路了
Whatever Hartley's using must be shorting out his comms.
我可以听到你衣服里...
I can hear the radio waves...
对对对  我记得
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I remember this.
传出的电波声
emanating from your suit.
现在还来得及
This could still work.
大概有1900兆赫
About 1,900 megahertz.
是他们在另一端听着吗
Are they on the other end listening?
他们会听到你死吗
Will they hear you die?
-不  他们会听到我  -痛扁你
- No. They're gonna hear you... - Get your ass kicked.
好吧
Okay.
这就把你吓跑了吗
Is that all it takes to scare you off?
而他却选择了你  而不是我
And he chose you over me?
我的通讯器  你是谁
My comms? Who are you?
我现在没时间给你解释
I don't have time to explain this to you right now.
我没懂  你是我吗
I don't understand. You're me.
抱歉  我必须这么做
I'm sorry, but I have to do this.
你总会明白的
This'll all make sense eventually.
你在哪里  被选中的那位
Where are you, oh, chosen one?
又抓到你了
Got ya again.
看来你不像大家说的那么聪明
Looks like you're not as smart as everyone says, huh?
聪明到看清了
Smart enough to have figured out
哈里森·威尔斯的真面目
who Harrison Wells really is.
我知道他的秘密
You see, I know his secret.
巴里  能听到吗
Barry, are you there?
听得到  我回来了
Yeah, yeah, I'm back.
带哈特利一起回来
I'm bringing Hartley in.
扫面仪识别出你耳朵里有外来金属物
Scanners picking up foreign metallic objects in your ears.
-取出来  -不行
- Take 'em out. - I can't.
尖端科研实验室爆炸时我头部受了创伤
I suffered head trauma when S.T.A.R. Labs exploded.
我的听觉严重受损
My hearing was severely damaged.
取出这些  我的痛苦你们无法体会
Without these, I am in pain you can only imagine.
西斯科  检查他耳朵里的东西
Cisco, see if the devices in his ears
能产生低强度电磁脉冲吗
are generating any low level electromagnetic pulses.
你要我扫瞄电磁脉冲炸弹吗
You want me to scan for E-bombs?
我是说  你难道不觉得
I just--I mean, don't you think
可能就是那东西干扰了通讯器
that could've been what was interfering with the comms?
看啊
Well, well.
想给我们上演《碟中谍》吗
Trying to go all "Mission: Impossible" on us?
想用那玩意儿逃出去
Use those things to bust out of here?
一切尽在不言中
用点刺激的声音来缓解他的耳鸣
Pump in some sound stimuli to counteract his tinnitus.
我们再做个不爆炸的替代物给他
Then we'll make some nonexplosive replacements for him.
晚点再处理你
Deal with you later.
取出来  哈特利  快点
Take them out, Hartley. Now.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells.
你刚对哈特利的观察
That was quite an observation you had
相当不错  艾伦先生
about Hartley in there, Mr. Allen.
是啊  只是感觉打败他太容易了
Yeah, it just seemed too easy taking him down, you know?
可能是因为你速度变快了
Well, the likely reason for that is you're getting faster.
其实我正想谈谈这事
Actually, I wanted to talk to you about that.
我想到咱们给我提速的方式
It occurred to me that maybe we've been going about
可能不太对
improving my speed the wrong way.
为什么
How so?
我一直在学习奔跑的不同技巧
I've been learning different techniques involved in running,
但是我想
and I was thinking
速度中所涉及的科学
that there's just as much science involved in speed
与任何身体和技术一样重要
as anything physical or technical.
我不知道要怎么在奔跑时运用起来
I just can't figure out how to apply it to me when I run.
要有人能帮我的话  那就是你了
Thought if anybody could help me, it'd be you.
你刚刚写下的这个  是某种速度公式
This is quite the... speed equation you've concocted here,
对吧  小艾先生
isn't it, Mr. Al?
对  我空闲的时候读了很多东西
Yeah, I've been doing a lot of reading in my downtime.
到底是什么启发你用这...
What on earth inspired you to adopt such a--
该叫这什么呢  旁门左道
what should we call this-- unorthodox approach?
我只知道我不是现今世上速度最快的人
I just know that I'm not the fastest man alive,
我需要变得更快  非常快
and I need to be faster, a lot faster,
才能够打倒那个黄衣人
if I'm ever gonna be able to take down the Man in Yellow.
所以你怎么看  能帮我吗
So what do you think? Can you help me?
看看我能帮到什么
Let me see what I can do.
中城警局
你好  乔
Hey, Joe.
你好  艾迪
Hey, Eddie.
午饭肯定吃的不错
Must have been a good lunch.
爱瑞丝是我同居的第一个女友
Iris is the first girlfriend I've ever lived with,
所以一切都很新鲜刺激
so it's all very new and exciting.
新鲜  行  刺激  不行
New? Yes. Exciting? No.
抱歉  我总是忘记你是她爸
Sorry. Somehow I keep forgetting you're her dad.
为了咱俩你还是记住了
Hey, try to remember for both our sakes.
过来
Come here.
我想过你对威尔斯的想法
I was thinking about what you said about Wells,
你说他有点不正常
how there's something off about him.
我要你帮我个忙  悄悄地
I need you to do something for me, off the books.
乔  拜托
Joe, come on.
相信我  艾迪
Just trust me, Eddie.
好  什么事
Okay. What?
再去他家彻底搜查一次
Go back to his house. Search everything.
有人吗
Someone there?
什么鬼
What the hell?
中城警局
CCPD.
我肯定他们能应付得了  对吧
I'm sure they have it handled, right?
不
No.
你得去帮忙
You need to go.
奔跑吧  巴里
Run, Barry.
大家没事吧
Is everyone okay?
-巴里  -什么事
- Barry. - Yeah?
-你得把那遮住  -对  好的
- You should cover that up. - Oh, right, yeah.
-谢谢  -乔
- Thanks. - Joe.
在外边没找到  它就这么凭空消失了
No sign of it outside. It just disappeared.
-你好  巴仔  -你好  艾迪
- Hey, Bar. - Hey, Eddie.
知道那玩意会是什么吗
Any idea what that thing could be?
不  我还不知道
No, I don't know. Not yet.
我查明了就告诉你
If I figured out I'll let you know.
这座城真是越来越离奇了
Things just keep getting more and more strange in this city.
是的  没错
Yeah, they do.
我去看下爱瑞丝  给她报个平安
I'm gonna check in with Iris, let her know I'm okay.
-很好  -好的  回见巴仔
- Great. - All right, see ya, Bar.
你究竟是怎么回事
What the hell's going on with you?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
听着  我知道你对爱瑞丝表达过爱意
Look, I know you told Iris that you love her,
但你说对爱瑞丝和艾迪的事已经看开了
but you said you'd moved past this whole Eddie and Iris thing.
是的  乔  我看开了
I have, Joe. I have.
那你为什么对艾迪举止反常
Then why are you being so weird to Eddie?
好吧  其实  抱歉
Okay, um, look. I'm sorry.
让我先处理好这些事  好吗
Let me just take care of all this, okay?
我过后会找你谈的  我保证
I'll talk to you later, I promise.
好吧  但要尽快
Fine. But soon.
尽快  是啊
Soon, yeah.
出什么事了
What's going on?
你懂的  在想办法弄清楚
Oh, you know, just trying to figure out
如何找到这个正在中城
how to find this Dementor that's apparently
四处游荡的摄魂怪
roaming through Central City right now.
我猜是它拜访了中城警局
I assume that was the cause of the CCPD alarm.
确实是  它袭击了我的实验室
Yeah, actually, it attacked my lab.
-你看到它了  -没  我没看见
- You saw it? - No, I didn't see it, no.
我...我没有及时赶到
I di--um--well, I didn't get there in time,
但我以前见过它
but I have seen it before.
在哪
Where?
其实就是今天早些
It was earlier today, actually,
当时我正要去抓哈特利
when I was running to take Hartley down.
是吗  你现在才告诉我们
Uh-huh. You're just mentioning this now?
我不知道它是什么
I-I didn't know what it was.
我以为是幻觉之类的  我不清楚
I thought it was some sort of illusion. I don't know.
好  我们必须在它伤及无辜之前找到它
Okay, well, we need to find it before it hurts somebody.
-你能追踪它吗  -你们是怎么了
- Can you track it? - What is it with you guys?
我又没有超感能力之类的
It's like you think I have ESP or something.
没办法突然感知东西在哪
I can't just magically sense where things are.
能做些什么  西斯科
What can you do, Cisco?
我想重新配置
I'm thinking I can reconfigure
尖端科研实验室的卫星去找
the S.T.A.R. Labs satellite to look for it.
不过要花些时间
Um, it might take some time though.
去做吧
Do it.
与此同时  艾伦先生请跟我来
In the meantime, Mr. Allen, come with me.
请坐
Have a seat.
是关于速度公式的事吗
Is this about the speed equation?
实际上是的
As a matter of fact, it is.
太好了  好的  很好
Oh, great. Okay, good.
-所以你弄明白了  -没错
- So you figured it out? - Mm-hmm.
是的  我弄明白了
Yes. I've figured it out.
说吧  你是谁
Now, who are you?
我是说  你的真实身份是谁
I mean, who are you really?
威尔斯博士  你在干什么
Dr. Wells, what are you doing?
这些都说不通
None of it adds up.
通讯器受干扰  速度公式
The interference with the comms, the speed equation,
时间亡灵
the Time Wraith.
这是它们的名字  时间亡灵
That's what we call them. Time Wraiths.
很吓人是吧
Scary, aren't they?
我想  "糟了  时间亡灵找到我了"
I thought, "Oh, no, a Time Wraith has found me."
然后又想  "不不不"
But then I thought, "No, no , no."
"你是有分寸的人"
"You know what you're doing."
时间亡灵专门追踪那些
Now, the Time Wraith is after someone
穿越了时间...
who's travelled through time...
却毫无分寸的人
and doesn't know what they're doing.
威尔斯博士  别闹了  是我
Dr. Wells, come on. It's me.
我是巴里  我不是...
It's--it's Barry. I don't--
真的吗
Really?
你很厉害
You are good.
你很厉害  我差点就信了  除了...
You are good, and I would believe you, except that...
没反应
Nothing?
我这样移动  你竟无动于衷
I move like this, you barely flinch.
你知道我的身份
You know who I am.
对不对
Don't you?
而且你来自未来
And you're from the future.
我是怎么知道的
Do you know how I know that?
因为我还没教我的巴里·艾伦
Because I haven't taught my Barry Allen
如何穿越物体
how to phase through objects... yet.
放我出去  斯旺
Let me out of here, Thawne.
我知道
I know.
你不好受
You're upset.
但听到这个名字我感觉不错
But it does me good to hear that name again.
现在来说更重要的问题
Now, onto the bigger question.
你为什么来这
Why are you here?
因为我想跑得更快
Because I want to go faster,
而且只有你能教我
and you're the only one who can teach me.
你是唯一解开过那个公式的人
You're the only one who's figured out the equation.
神速力
The Speed Force.
你熟练使用它
You've manipulated it.
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
不
No.
不对  不对  不对
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不对
No.
你来这里  一定是出了什么状况
You'd only come here if something went wrong.
如果你依然活着
If you're still alive,
就意味着...
then that means...
我没能打败你
I haven't beaten you.
如果你依然活着
If you're still alive...
意味着我的计划失败了
that means my plan fails.
如果我的计划失败
And if my plan fails,
我也就回不了家  这样的话  那不如
I don't get to go home, and if that's the case, well, then--
不不不  慢着  恰恰相反
No, no, no! Hey, hey, hey! It's the opposite!
恰恰相反
It's the opposite!
你骗过了我  你抑制了我的速度
It--you trick me. You harness my speed.
我们用粒子加速器给你建立了
We turn on the accelerator to create a path
回家的通道
for you to go home.
我穿越到过去
I go back in time.
你回到你的时代
You go back to yours.
你赢了
You won.
是的
Yeah.
那你为什么来这
Then why are you here?
你为什么来现在
Why are you here now?
因为我穿越到过去时  形成了一个奇点
Because when I got back, a singularity had formed.
只有来这我才能学会
And now the only way for me to learn how to get faster
让速度更快并阻止奇点的产生
and stop the singularity from happening was to come here.
来现在
Now.
这真是个好消息
Well, that's good to know.
只是...
There's just...
只是突然想到一件事
just one thing that occurs to me.
我不需要你
I don't need you.
是吗
Do I?
当然是不需要这个你
Not this you certainly.
你在来这里之前
You probably should've thought of that
也许该想到这点
before you came back here.
可惜
Shame...
你大老远跑回这里
You ran all the way back here
就为找死吗
just to die.
你杀了我  巴里
You kill me-- Barry--
这个巴里  你的巴里
this Barry, your Barry,
他就会知道一切
he learns it all.
我藏了一封信告诉他之后的结局
There's a hidden letter telling him how it ends,
告诉他如何打败你  告诉他一切
how to beat you, everything.
如果我发生不测  你永远别想回家
Anything happens to me, you never make it back home.
继续啊
Go on.
杀了我  斯旺
Kill me, Thawne.
看看结局如何
See how this all ends.
现在
Now,
你要帮我提升速度
you're gonna help me get faster.
拜托
Please.
我要知道运作原理
I want to know how these work.
我会告诉你  先把音乐关了
I'll tell you, just kill the music.
谢谢
Thanks.
这对护手  哈特利
The gauntlets, Hartley.
用的是什么频率
What kind of frequency is this?
西斯科  它来了
Cisco, it's here!
-它来了  -快进牢房  快
- It's coming! - Inside the cell, now!
抱歉  什么来了
Uh, sorry. What's coming?
我了个哈利波特啊
Holy Harry Potter.
这也太魔幻了吧
Okay. Well, isn't this fantastic?
我们在这里面很安全
Look, we're gonna be safe in here.
这些牢房是...
These cells are--
牢不可破吗
Impenetrable?
巴里  威尔斯博士
Barry! Dr. Wells!
好了  我们得去救他们
All right. We have to help them.
你让它追着你到这里
You let it track you here.
放我出去  快点
Get me out of here! Come on!
如果那东西跟着我  捣乱我的计划
If that thing comes after me and messes with my plans,
你们就死定了
you're all dead.
他们在哪
Where are they?
好吧  大家往后退
Okay, let's step back.
你会把玻璃弄碎的
You'll shatter the glass.
你有更好的办法吗
You got a better plan?
没错  把护手给我
As a matter of fact, give me those.
不行
No!
快点  西斯科
Now, Cisco!
你要做什么
What are you gonna do?
这些牢房的喇叭遍及尖端科研实验室
These cells have speakers linked throughout S.T.A.R. Labs.
-然后呢  -我可以操纵护手
- Yes, and? - I rigged these gauntlets
如果护手解体就能发出毁灭性的信号
to emit a destructive signal if ever they're disarmed.
只要我能找到外面
If I can just find the right frequency
那个怪物的正确频率
of whatever the hell that thing is,
这么说吧  你们得庆幸有我在
well, let's just say you'll be glad you're in here with me.
抱歉我们来晚了
I'm sorry that we didn't come sooner.
没事  墨汁消失了  没有发现
It's all right, Inky's gone. I don't see anything.
如果没有哈特利
You know, we'd be toast
和那对护手  我们就死定了
if wasn't for Hartley and those gauntlets.
自卫本能起到了很多的作用
Well, self-preservation is a very strong motivator,
但是没我同意  他要待在牢里
but he stays in the cell until I say otherwise.
好吧  只是这么一说
Okay, I'm just saying.
这东西
So the two places
袭击了这里和中城警局两个地方
this thing has attacked are here and CCPD.
共同点是...
The common denominator being--
我  嗯  我知道
Me. Yeah, I know.
我只是不知道为什么
I just-- I don't know why.
你肯定做了什么事激怒了他
Well, you must have done something to piss him off.
无匹配项
卫星毫无发现
Satellite hasn't found anything.
我们要找到解决这问题更永久的方法
We need to find a more permanent solution to this problem.
从修复哈特利的护手开始
Start by repairing Hartley's gauntlets.
这是很好的开端
That's about as good a first step as any.
-我有些零件可以用  -开始吧
- I got some parts for it. - Let's go for it.
你不知道如何阻止时间亡灵吗
You don't know how to stop a Time Wraith?
没人知道
None of us do.
所以在穿越时我们一直尽量避开它们
That's why we always try and avoid them in our travels.
我们
"We"?
极速者不止我们俩  明白吗
Speedsters-- we're not the only two out there, you know?
这不是我第一次穿越时间
This isn't the first time I've time traveled.
之前我怎么从未见过它们
How come I've never seen one of these until now?
因为你的运气到头了
Because you ran out of luck.
时间亡灵非常讨厌
And Time Wraiths hate it
极速者篡改时间线
when speedsters manipulate the timeline,
现在它要想尽办法终结你
and now that thing's gonna do everything it can to end you.
只能这样了
Here's what we're gonna do.
你去中城警局
You're gonna go to CCPD.
看看能找到些什么
You're gonna see what you can find to
帮忙阻止它  我也会在这里想办法
help us stop this thing-- I'll do the same here.
我应该找什么
Well, what am I supposed to be looking for?
你是鉴证专员  动动脑子
You're in forensics. Figure something out.
那能让我提升速度的公式呢
Hey, what about the equation? Me getting faster?
如果阻止不了时间亡灵
If we don't stop this thing,
我也没必要教你了
there's gonna be no point in me teaching you anything.
没发现微量元素  指纹
No trace elements, no prints,
除了这烂摊子  没发现它来过的痕迹
no sign that it was ever here except the whole mess.
知道它在找什么吗
Any idea what it was looking for?
-找我  -什么  为什么
- Me. - What, why?
我做了触怒它的事
It doesn't like something that I did.
究竟是什么事
And what exactly would that be?
乔  辛格叫你去他办公室
Joe, Singh needs you in his office.
艾迪  有空吗
Hey, Eddie, do you have a second?
我要去帮乔核实一条线索
I kind of got to go check out a lead for Joe.
其实我想说说爱瑞丝的生日
Okay, actually this is for Iris's birthday.
还有两个月呢
That's two months from now.
嗯  不  我知道  你说得对
Yeah, no, I know. You're right.
我只是想给她拍段视频
I just-- um, I want to make a video montage for her,
她身边的每个人  和她的出现如何
just everybody in her life and how her being in your life
让你的生活更美好
has made it better.
这主意听上去不错
That sounds great, yeah.
我会想点话来说的
I'll think of something to say.
我们可以现在录吗
Can we do it now?
巴里  我真的有事要做
Barry, I really got to go do this thing.
我  我知道  真的
I-I know. I really--
但我今天就得把它录好
It's just I kind of have to get it today.
-好吧  -好的  太棒了
- Sure. - All right, great.
说些心里话就好
Just, um-- just speak from the heart.
就像  就像是
Talk as if-- talk as if,
这是你能对她说的最后一番话
it was the last thing you could ever say to her.
好的
Okay.
开始吧
Go ahead.
爱瑞丝对我来说意味着什么
What does Iris mean to me?
所以这护手能被修好吗
So can these gauntlets be salvaged?
它们的电子枪被烧坏了
Their electron guns are fried.
所以导致波管短路
So it shorted the wave tubes...
然后摧毁了扩音器
And destroyed the amplifiers.
是的  但是说句实话
Yeah, but to be honest with you,
我不知道怎么控制频率方差
I don't know how to manipulate the frequency variance.
哈特利知道
Hartley would know.
是他做了这副护手
He's the one who did it.
去看他能不能帮忙  但他得待在牢房里
See if he can help, but he stays in the cell.
然后怎么办  那东西还会回来的
But then what? That thing's gonna come back.
我不知道
I don't know.
他在哪儿  另一个闪电侠呢
Where is he? Where's the other Flash?
在这儿呢
Right here.
好吧  今天和我预想的可不太一样
Okay. Not how I expected today to turn out.
是啊
Yeah.
好吧  所以我  你是  你是谁
Okay, so I'm--who are-- who are you?
他是谁  你又是谁
Who is he? Who are you?
你说啥  我是巴里  我是巴里啊
What do you--I'm Barry. I'm Barry.
-你认识的巴里  他是  -你的二重身
- Your Barry. He's...  - Your doppelganger.
不  现在还不是
No, not yet.
我就是你  巴里
I am you, Barry.
只是  不太一样
Just...different.
等一下  我们怎么知道哪个才是真正的巴里
Wait a second, how do we know which one's the real Barry?
哥们  好吧  我和你一起看了《星际迷航2》
Dude, okay, I've watched "Wrath of Khan" with you
-还看了五遍  -冒牌货
- Like five times. - Imposter!
是啊  每次看到结尾  你都会转身对我说
Yeah, and every time at the end, you turn to me and you say,
我一直都会是你的朋友
"I have been and always shall be your friend."
你才是冒牌货
You, imposter!
到底发生了什么
What is going on here?
伙计们  我很抱歉  这一切本不该发生的
Okay, guys, I'm sorry. This was not supposed to happen.
凯特琳做的麻醉镖
The tranq dart that Caitlin made
本该持续更长时间的
was supposed to last a lot longer.
我没有给他什么麻醉镖
I did not give him a tranq dart.
好吧  不是  是  不是你
Okay, no, yes, not you,
是来自我的那个时间点的你
the you from the time that I am from.
你的时间点
The time that you are from?
我觉得他是想说他来自未来
I think what he's trying to say is he's from the future.
-未来  -是的
- The future? - Yeah.
- The future? - Yes.
-等下  未来  -是的
- Wait, the future? - Yes.
这是说我可以时间旅行吗
Are we saying I can time-travel?
未来的某天
One day.
这就解释了标志上的白色
Oh, that explains the white on the symbol.
好的  等一下
Well, wait a second.
如果我们现在改了你的徽章
Suppose we now change your emblem.
会不会是因为我们从你这儿得到启发
Will it be because we got the idea from this?
-或者  我是说  这意味着  -闭嘴
- Or, I mean, that would mean--  - Stop talking.
你也闭嘴  行吗
You stop talking too, all right?
你说得越多  时间线被扰得越乱
More you say, the more the timeline is disrupted.
现在我猜你出现在这里
Now I'm going to assume that your presence here
就是那个东西来袭击我们的原因
is the reason that thing is attacking us.
什么  什么东西
What? What thing?
你没看过《恐怖幽灵》吗
Have you ever seen "The Frighteners"?
有点像那个  但更可怕也更快
It's sort of like that, but scarier and faster,
而且它是追着你的  追着他
and it's after you--after him.
是的  我刚来时它就开始追我了
Yeah, it's been chasing me ever since I got here.
好的  所以我们怎么阻止它呢
Okay, so how do we stop it?
我们不知道
We don't know.
那我们怎么办
Then what are we gonna do?
做我们唯一能做的事
The one thing we can.
怎么  我们来这儿做什么
What? What are we doing here?
我们在这儿是为了解答你的速度公式
We're here for the answer to your speed equation--
你时间旅行回到这个时间点的原因
the reason that you traveled back to this time,
也是跑得更快的秘诀
and the key to running faster.
超光速粒子增强器
Tachyon enhancement.
这可不是咱们说好的
This was not the deal.
如果你觉得我会一步一步地教你
If you think that I'm gonna hold your hand this entire way,
那你真是错得离谱
you're sadly mistaken.
你所需的一切都在这个驱动里
Everything you need is on this drive.
你跟着它的指示  就能够增强
You follow its instructions, you will enhance
你体内的神速力  并跑得更快
the Speed Force in your system and run faster...
超乎你想像的快
than you ever thought possible.
如果这个不起效的话
If this doesn't work,
我会回来的
I'm coming back.
威尔斯博士  我们需要你
Dr. Wells, we need you.
是时候回家了  闪电侠
Time to go home, Flash.
好的  我们的卫星终于找到了
Okay, our satellite has finally found
找到匹配目标
我们的亡灵朋友  而它要回来了
our floating friend and it's coming back.
你得走了
You need to go.
我得知道怎么阻止它
I need to know how to stop it.
巴里
Barry--
现在不是时候  等我回来再说
Not now. When I get back.
你们还有一年的时间来想办法
You guys have a year to figure it out.
好的  我们会想出办法的
Okay. We'll figure something out.
西斯科  过来一下
Cisco, come here.
哈特利知道罗尼在哪儿
Hartley knows where Ronnie is.
好的  你说啥
Okay. What?
它来了
It's coming.
你现在就得走
You need to leave now.
好的
Yeah.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
时间亡灵
巴里  它来了
Barry, here it comes.
没有起效  它在减慢他的速度
It's not working. It's slowing him down.
不会太久
Not for long.
不  巴里
No! Barry!
真酷
Cool.
-它来了  -你去了吗
- It's coming! - Did you even go?
-是时间亡灵  -好名字
- The Time Wraith. - That's a good name.
看来是去了
Looks like that's a yes.
你们找到阻止它的方法了吗
Did you figure out how to stop it?
该死  我们以为找到了
Damn! We thought so!
巴里
Barry!
我突然想到
I suddenly realized.
低频率  高强度
Low frequency, high intensity.
我就知道
I knew that.
巴里  旅程如何
Barry. How was your trip?
除了有个时间亡灵来到这儿
So aside form the fact that a Time Wraith came over here
差点杀了我们  其余怎么样
and nearly killed us, how did it go?
很有意思
It was interesting.
好的有意思还是坏的有意思
Good interesting or bad interesting?
因为两种都有可能
'Cause that could go either way.
目前看来  还好
So far so... good.
从地球去其它星球可不容易
我们要和你说多少次  哈特利
How many times do we have to tell you, Hartley?
自从邪恶版威尔斯消失之后
Ever since Evil Wells got erased from existence,
这里没人说拉丁语了
no one speaks Latin around here anymore.
一如往常  和你们各位一起
Well, as always, it's been a pleasure
完成这个小项目  很愉快
working with you all on this little project.
如果以后还有什么需要  给我打电话
If you need anything in the future, call me.
我晚餐要迟到了
I'm off to a late dinner.
晚餐  和特别的人吗
Mm, dinner. Anyone special?
非常特别  我的父母
Very. My parents.
怎么样  你让我在这里坐立不安
So? You got me on pins and needles over here.
速度公式怎么样了
What about the speed equation?
威尔斯告诉你该怎么做了吗
Did Wells tell you what you need to do?
我们看看吧
Well, let's see.
或许有密码保护
Maybe it's password protected?
逗我玩吗
Are you kidding me?
我刚受了那么多罪
After everything I just went through...
这根本不能用
this doesn't even work!
找到了
We got it.
-你还好吗  -我还好
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm okay.
虽然说在这个地球上
Altough it turns out it's easier to find
找一只两吨重的大猩猩比找十多岁的女儿容易
a two-ton gorilla on this earth than a teenage daughter.
真不知道我做了什么
I don't know what I've done.
你做了你认为你必须做的事
You did what you thought you had to do.
你为她不顾自己的安危
You risked your life to save her.
你带她来这儿  保护她远离极速
You brought her here to protect her from Zoom.
你做的是父亲做的事
You acted like a father.
"父亲做的事"
"Like a father."
你知道吗  我妻子还得...
You know, my wife had to--
还得说服我生儿育女
she had to talk me into having kids.
孩子  他们又小  又爱吵闹  爱乱跑
Kids, you know, they're-- they're small, loud, run around.
我本来只需要科学和工作
All I needed was my science and my job
就能得到快乐和幸福
for my joy and happiness.
可后来
And then...
我们有了她之后
the moment we had her...
我就只想得到她的爱
all that I wanted was her love.
而现在  我不知道我能不能再得到了
Now, I don't know if I'll ever see that again.
我最近做的每一个决定  似乎都
It seems every decision I've made lately has...
适得其反
backfired on me.
你只需要相信  从长远来看
You just have to trust that, in the long run,
那些决定是对的
you made the right ones.
我把你的晚餐盘子放进冰箱了
I put your plate from dinner in the fridge.
谢了
Thanks.
已经过了快一年了
It's been almost a year already.
你能相信吗
Can you believe that?
就是这样  爱瑞丝  一切都在继续向前
That's the thing, Iris. Everything keeps moving forward.
问题是  你什么时候能继续呢
Question is, when will you?
我不知道  巴里
I don't know, Barry.
我找到一个东西
Well, I found something
我想或许有帮助
that I think might help.
我去年和大家一起做了这个视频小合集
I was putting together this little video montage
想在你生日时送给你  结果...
for your birthday last year with everybody, and...
发生了那些事
everything happened.
不过  你看看吧
But, take a look.
我想会有帮助
I think it might help.
好
Okay.
爱瑞丝对我意味着什么
What does Iris mean to me?
有很多次  我都觉得
You know, a lot of times I have a hard time
思考怎么和人说话很困难
figuring out what to say to people,
但是跟你说话时  爱瑞丝  就不会了
but when it comes to you, Iris, I don't.
因为和你在一起  本来觉得艰难的事
Because with you, everything that used to feel tough
就不再艰难了
just doesn't anymore.
这是我爱你的原因之一
It's one of the things I love about you.
你不需要我
You don't need me.
你可以自己应对一切
You can handle anything on your own
因为你无所畏惧  独立自主
because you're fearless and independent...
充满爱和善良
loving, kind.
你无疑是
You are without question
我做过的最好的决定  爱瑞丝·韦斯特
the best decision I ever made, Iris West.
我从没感谢你  选择和我在一起
And I've never thanked you for choosing to be with me
因为和你一起的每一天都是恩赐
because each day with you is a gift.
所以  谢谢你
So, thank you.
你应该拥有整个世界  爱瑞丝
You deserve the world, Iris.
你应该一生幸福
You deserve to be happy the rest of your life,
再没有人比我更希望如此了
and no one wants that more for you than me.
生日快乐  宝贝  我爱你
Happy birthday, baby. I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
有时候  向前看的唯一方式
Sometimes the only way to move forward
就是重温过去那些
is to revisit the things in your past
牵绊着你的事
that were holding you back.
你必须迎面去解决
You have to deal with them head on,
不管它们有多可怕
no matter how scary they may be.
因为一旦我们这么做了  就会发现
Because once we do, you'll see
你能比自己想像的走得更远
that you can go further than you ever imagined.
我来找你了
I'm coming for you.